# MUHAMMAD AMMAR UL HASSAN

Phone: (+82) 10-2637-3994

Email: <a href="mailto:ammar.instantsoft@gmail.com/ammar91@soongsil.ac.kr">ammar91@soongsil.ac.kr</a> Location: Gwanak-gu, Bongcheon-dong, Seoul, South Korea

DOB: 1991/01/01, Nationality: Pakistan GitHub: https://github.com/ammar-deep

Personal Website: <a href="https://ammar-deep.github.io">https://ammar-deep.github.io</a>



## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Graduate research assistant with 4 years of active research & development experience in Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Classification, Object detection, Generative modeling, Generative Adversarial Networks, Image-to-Image translation (Domain transfer), Metric learning, Contrastive learning, Self-supervised learning, Few-shot image generation, Deep learning frameworks, and 2 years of professional experience in Web application development.

#### **EDUCATION**

**PhD** Soongsil University, Computer Science & Engineering Expected in Feb 2023

Dissertation: "Unsupervised Image Generation for Multiple Domains based on

Mixing Regularization and Projection Encoder"

Advisor: Prof. Jaeyoung Choi

MS Soongsil University, Computer Science & Engineering Aug 2018

Thesis: "FreeType Outlet Adapter (FOA): A module for adding new functionality

inside the FreeType rasterizer." Advisor: Prof. Jaeyoung Choi

**BS** International Islamic University, Software Engineering Aug 2013

Final Project: Tic Tac Toe game in android using SMS

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Graduate Research Assistant**

2016 – present

System Software Lab, Soongsil University, Seoul, South Korea

My Ph.D. research focuses on computer vision, with applications in text image synthesis and manipulation, unsupervised image generation, image-to-image translation, and self-supervised learning. Below are a few of the primary research projects on which I've worked.

### 1. Controllable Unsupervised Generative Model

- Designed a controllable unsupervised generative adversarial network architecture
- Disentangled the content and style in an unsupervised fashion

- Applications in image style transfer, attribute manipulation, domain transfer, etc. without label supervision

#### 2. Few-shot Font Generation

- Developed Metric learning and Contrastive learning-based network architectures
  - Learning font style latent space for few-shot font generation
- Component-guided Korean and Chinese font generation algorithms
- Applications in text image editing, font library creation, cross-lingual font generation

## 3. Font Family Generation

- Font family data collection, preprocessing, and labeling
- Developed a generative model for real-time font family generation
- Applications in Variable font for typeface variations

### 4. Text Image Skeletonization

- Character image skeletonization using an end-to-end generative adversarial network (GAN)
- Developed Skeleton-driven Korean font synthesis model
- Applications in object representation, manipulation, tracking, recognition

### 5. MetaFont Module for FreeType rasterizer

- Rasterized MetaFont in Linux operating system
- Integrated driver module of MetaFont in FreeType rasterizer

**Web Developer** 2014 – 2016

Tangent Technologies Pvt Ltd, Islamabad, Pakistan

- Developed, designed, and managed web applications
- Built and deployed plugins and extensions for WordPress and OpenCart
  - DHL and Endicia Postage label printing extensions for OpenCart
- Collaborated closely with other team members to efficiently plan, design, and develop robust solutions

### **SKILLS**

**Computer Vision:** Generative modeling, Classification, Object detection **Programming Languages**: PHP, Python, C (knowledgeable), C++ (knowledgeable)

Deep Learning Frameworks: PyTorch, TensorFlow

Databases: MySQL

Web Dev: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, WordPress, OpenCart

Misc.: Academic research, teaching, training, LATEX typesetting, and publishing

## **Soongsil University**

March 2021 to Jun 2021

**Head TA** for Deep learning programming (5041345801)

- Taught Applications of Deep Neural Networks by Jeff Heaton
- Python programming language to implement deep learning using TensorFlow 2.0

# **Korean Society of Computational Science and Engineering**

Dec 2020

**Invited Lecturer** for Machine Learning Winter School (KSCSE)

- Tutorial on Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs)
- TensorFlow 2.0
- Tutorial details on Website

### **AMGCC Workshop**

Aug 2020

Talk on Font Generation trends using Machine Learning

- Discussed various state-of-the-arts font generation methods
- Presented our work on font generation and future directions

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

My Google Scholar profile contains a comprehensive listing of my publications.

#### **Publications**

**Hassan, A.** U., Memon, I., and Choi, J., "Real-time high quality font generation with conditional font gan," Expert Systems with Applications, 213, 118907. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2022.118907">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2022.118907</a>. (2022)

**Hassan, A. U.,** and Choi, J., "Fontnet: Closing the gap to font designer performance in font synthesis," AI for Content Creation (AI4CC), CVPR, 2022.

**Hassan, A.** U., Ahmed, H., and Choi, J., "Unpaired font family synthesis using conditional generative adversarial networks," Knowledge-Based Systems, 229, 107304. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.knosys.2021.107304. (2021)

Ko, D. H., **Hassan, A. U.**, Suk, J., and Choi, J., "SKFont: Skeleton-driven Korean font generator with conditional deep adversarial networks," International Journal on Document Analysis and Recognition (IJDAR), 1–13. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10032-021-00374-4">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10032-021-00374-4</a>

Ko, D. H., **Hassan, A.** U., Majeed, S., and Choi, J., "Skelgan: A font image skeletonization method. Journal of Information Processing Systems," Journal of Information Processing Systems, 17(1), 1–13.

### **PATENTS**

**Hassan, A. U.,** and Choi, J., "METHOD AND APPARATUS FOR GENERATING FONT FAMILY USING DEEP LEARNNING,", Soongsil University Industry-Academic Cooperation Foundation, Patent, No. 2-2006-027849-9 (Korea), 2022.

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

# **International Graduate Research Scholarship**

2018 – present

Soongsil University

# **Best Paper Bronze award**

2020

International Conference on Smart Media and Applications (SMA)

# **International Graduate Research Scholarship**

2016 - 2018

Soongsil University

# **Federal Government Scholarship**

2009 - 2013

Given to undergraduates whose GPA is high-ranking in his/her own major University

#### **LANGUAGES**

English: Strong reading, writing. and speaking competencies

Korean: Learner

Urdu / Hindi: Native Language

### REFERENCES

Available on Request